

ARNAUD PANNATIER

PhD Candidate in Attention-based models

PhD Candidate, within the Machine Learning group led by Professor François Fleuret (Idiap Research Institute / EPFL), primarily focusing on attention models and their adaptability to various domains, ranging from wind prediction, air traffic control assistance, vision, to natural language processing. I collaborate closely with companies on practical problems using real-world data.

EDUCATION

PhD in Machine Learning

Innosuisse, with SkySoft ATM Idiap Research Institute / EPFL 2020 - 2024

Master in Computer Sciences and Engineering

Math Faculty, EPFL 2017 - 2020

Bachelor in Physics

Physics Faculty, EPFL 2014 - 2017

LANGUES

French: Native speaker

English: Fluent

German: Basic knowledge

PUBLICATIONS

A. Pannatier, K. Matoba, F. Fleuret **Inference from Real-World Sparse Measurements** under review at International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024

F. Mai, A. Pannatier, F. Fehr, H. Chen, F. Marelli, F. Fleuret, J. Henderson **HyperMixer: An MLP-based Low Cost Alternative to Transformers.** In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2023.* DOI: 10.18653/v1/2023.acl-long.871

A. Pannatier, R. Picatoste, and F. Fleuret. **Efficient Wind Speed Nowcasting with GPU-Accelerated Nearest Neighbors Algorithm.** In *Proceedings of the SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM), 2022.* DOI: 10.1137/1.9781611977172.37

A. Pannatier A Control Plane in Time and Space for Locality-Preserving Blockchains In Master Thesis, Decentralized Distributed Systems Laboratory (DEDIS), EPFL, 2020

Price: Kudelski Award

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, EPFL

- Advanced Analysis 1-2 Pr. Stubbe, 2016, 2017, 2018
- Analysis 2 Pr. Buffoni, 2018
- Advanced Analysis 3 Pr. Krieger, 2018
- Introduction à l'apprentissage automatique Pr. Liebling, 2020, 2023
- Deep Learning Pr. Fleuret, 2021, 2022
- Information, Computation, Communication Pr. Chappelier, 2020, 2022, 2023

Substitute Math Teacher

Lycée Collège de la Planta Mathematics, Advanced Mathematics Mme Jordan, Mme Veuthey, Mr. Petit 1-5e, 2017 - 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software engineer

Caelum Fintech SA, Technopôle 2018 - 2020 (Part time)

INTERESTS

Hiking

Hiked from home (VS/CH) to Santiago de Compostella (ES) 2300 km in 83 days (April 2019 - July 2019)

Chess

Treasurer of the Union Valaisanne des Échecs (UVE-WSB) Play with Sion 1 (1st League, previously League B) Ex-Captain of Chess Team Valais 2 (2nd league)

INFORMATIONS

Rue des Longs-Prés 40 3960 Sierre +41 77 439 30 16 arnaud.pannatier@idiap.ch https://arnaudpannatier.ch

Born September 20, 1995, in Sion, Valais Married, two children (born 2022, 2023)